Mohanad Ghanim CV.

Professional profile

A multi-skilled operation technician with considerable experience in the oil and gas industry of the Iraq with an extensive operations background in process commissioning, shutdowns, start-ups, isolation procedures and PTW systems. A team player with the proven ability to supervise and train production teams in operations procedures and ISSOW PTW systems. A quick learner, adaptable to change, and a good problem solver, demonstrating the self-motivation and organization required to meet targets and deadlines.

Career history

2016—Present Operator Technician, Gazprom Neft, Onshore Processing Facility

Arriving on the OPF I became the member of multinational team and the team player of the specialists from different companies. Started again as field operator. Equipment being operated here is Crude oil, condensate & NGL pumps, Booster and High pressure (85 brag) center fugal compressors, Gas Sweetening unit, Gas stabilization ,NGL,LPG ,Fire system , Methanol , Anti foam, Dew point control units, Glycol regeneration unit and Pigging facility.

2014 – 2016 Commissioning Operator, DACO. In WEST QURNA Oil field Iraq - Basra ,Al-Ahdab Oil field and Zubaidiah power plant.

Started as a Field Operator and for the next 1 years I moved to the positions of Commissioning Engineer. Commissioning rotating equipment (compressors, pumps and Gas turbine and Static equipment.

2013-2014 Mechanical engineer, Delta AL-Wafi Co., Iraq - Baghdad I started as a RO Line water production process engineer,

my job was monitoring and maintain water line production's machines to ensure get our target of daily production.

2012-2013 Technical engineer assistant, Wasit company for fabric industrics

I worked as a technical engineer assistant to monitor and maintain sewing and knitting machines, air compressors and water treatment plant.

Education

B.Sc. In Mechanical engineering, and engineer in process automation and control. CPF Operator Diploma -Gazprom company

Courses, trainings and skills

- . Cpf operator Diploma
- Process and Mechanical Isolation Authority
- Authtorised Gas Tester
- Maintenance Integrity Execution(MIE)
- Ensure Safety Production(ESP)
- Operations Integrity(OI)
- Electrical, Mechanical and Instrumentation
- Working at height rescue and Confined space entry
- Integrated Safe System of Work(ISSOW)
- Advanced PC user skills: Adobe Acrobat, MS Word, Excel, Power Point, Email and Internet.
- Driver license "B" category

Personal details

th

Date of Birth: 20 August 1992.

Marital status: Married.

Citizenship: Iraqi.

Interests: Traveling, motorsports. Health: Excellent, non-smoker.

Summary

- Over 5 years in oil and gas industry
- Experience in managing and leading on gas processing facility
- High level of personal integrity, when faced with challenging circumstances
- Operational experience, commissioning, start-up and shutdown experience English, Arabic language